rockymountainatv.com 2019-07-29

# Privacy and Security - Rocky Mountain ATV/MC

#### Updated: 04/11/19

Rocky Mountain ATV/MC deals routinely with customer information as you visit and browse our website, create an account, place an order, or make a return. Rocky Mountain ATV/MC is committed to respecting your online privacy and has created this Privacy Policy to demonstrate our commitment to the protection of your personal information. This Privacy Policy applies to any personal information you provide to us, or that we collect through our website or other electronic forms of communication. By accessing or using any part of these sites or services, you agree to the collection and use of information according to this Privacy Policy. This page explains:

  * What personally identifiable information is collected from you through our websites, how it is used, and with whom it may be shared
  * The security procedures in place to protect your personal information
  * What choices are available to you regarding the use of your personal information
  * How you can correct any inaccuracies to your personal information

We are committed to respecting and protecting your information and would like you, our valued customers, to understand what information is collected, why we collect it, and how we protect it. 

  * What We Gather
  * How We Gather It
  * How We Protect It
  * How We Use It
  * Your Control
  * California Residents

### What We Gather

While using our websites to browse, create an account, or place an order, we may collect the following personal information from you:

  * Identifying Information: Including first and last name, mailing, shipping and billing addresses, e-mail address, phone numbers, and IP addresses
  * Device Information: Including device number, device model, operating system and version, device date and time, unique device identifiers. This is used to help us understand demographics, fix website errors, and to monitor and prevent fraud
  * Credit card information: Including credit card number, security code, and expiration date. This information is used to complete purchase transactions on our websites. Card numbers and security codes are not stored in our databases or servers
  * Commercial Information: Including purchase history, return and exchange information, product registry, and wish lists
  * Internet Activity Information: Including pages viewed, search terms used, and web access times
  * Age verification. When submitting a review or completing a product rebate form, we request that you verify you are over 18 years old, or we ask to know your age range.

This information is necessary to provide you with the requested products and services, and to stay responsive to your powersport needs. It not only helps us personalize offerings, but helps us discover and fight fraud. We store this information permanently unless otherwise directed, to process returns and provide warranty and customer support. 

### How We Gather Data

Rocky Mountain ATV/MC collects data to operate effectively and provide you with the best experience possible when using our websites. This data is collected in many ways. You provide us with personal information when you register for an account on our websites, place an order, add machines to your account profile, enter a contest or promotion or correspond with us by email, phone or an online chat. Additionally, we automatically collect data based on how you use our websites, products you search for, how you got to our websites, and other user behavior metrics utilizing analytics and cookies. 

#### Cookies and Similar Technologies

Cookies are small files stored on your devices that tell websites who you are. Rocky Mountain ATV/MC uses cookies to track how you use our site to create personalized experiences. For example, they remember which items you have added to your cart, or for what vehicle you are shopping. If you prefer not to use cookies, you may shut them off by changing the appropriate setting in your browser. Without cookies, however, we cannot accomplish many of the basic functions needed to create and process an order on our websites. We recommend you keep cookies activated. 

We have broken up our cookies into four categories to help you understand what they do.

  1. Essential: These cookies are required to use our website. For example, they are necessary to add items to your cart and checkout. 
  2. Performance: These cookies track how you interact with our website. For example, Google Analytics lets us know which pages on our website load slowly or are not optimized for mobile use. We use this information to make improvements to our user experience.
  3. Functionality: These cookies track information about you to make using our website easier. For example, if you add a machine to your profile to see which products fit it, we save that information so that you can select your machine easier the next time you are looking for products on our website.
  4. Marketing and Advertising: These cookies help us create targeted advertising experiences for you.

Additionally, Rocky Mountain ATV/MC utilizes third-party cookies to provide customized advertising for our customers. For example, if you looked at a particular product on our website, you may see that product in an advertisement when browsing another site. This type of tracking can be stopped by opting out of those advertisements on the respective third-party platform’s website. 

#### Disclosure of Information to Third Parties

Rocky Mountain ATV/MC does not sell your personal information to third parties. However, we may disclose your personal information to our subsidiaries and affiliates, along with our service providers and third-party processors to provide a better experience for customers using our websites. For example, we use a company that helps gather reviews on products by asking how you like a product after purchase. We also utilize third-party services to provide customized internal site search, to run our affiliate marketing program, to collect and remit sales tax, and to provide the best shipping rates possible. If subpoenaed or otherwise legally compelled, we will surrender any relevant personal information to the extent required by law. 

Below is a list of third-party affiliates Rocky Mountain ATV/MC works with. We have organized them into categories based on what they help us with. For your convenience, we have included a link to their privacy policies for reference. 

#### Marketing and Customer Service Management

#### Order Processing

RMATVMC utilizes a third party company to operate our online web chat feature. All information included in those chats is subject to the [LiveHelpNow privacy policy.](https://www.livehelpnow.net/policies/privacy) For questions about third-party data collection, please email [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#7f0c1a1c0a0d160b063f0d101c140612100a110b1e16111e0b09511c1012) and we will be happy to provide you with what personal data they may have about you, and how you can control that data. 

#### Analytics

Google Analytics is a service offered by Google that tracks and reports website traffic. Google uses the data collected to track and monitor the use of our websites. This data is shared with other Google services, which may use the collected data to contextualize and personalize the ads on its advertising network. 

You can opt-out of making your activity available to Google Analytics by installing the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on. The add-on prevents the Google Analytics JavaScript (ga.js, analytics.js, and dc.js) from sharing information with Google Analytics about website visits or activity. 

For more information on the privacy practices of Google, please visit the Google Privacy and Terms web page: <https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en>

#### International Transfer of Data

Your personal information is stored and processed on servers located in the United States of America for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. If you are a resident of a country outside of the United States, you agree as a part of this Privacy Policy to the global transfer, process, and storage of your personal information. 

### How We Protect It

Keeping your information secure is as important to us as it is to you. We want you to feel safe providing us with credit card numbers, phone numbers, and personal addresses. We maintain physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards reasonably necessary to ensure the protection of your personal information against loss, misuse, disclosure, and alteration 

Employees are educated on security protocols to ensure the safe and proper handling of your personal information. Only authorized employees are allowed access to stored personal information, and only for the explicit uses described in this Privacy Policy. Our company, websites, call center, and showrooms comply with Payment Card Industry Data Security Standards (PCI-DSS). Information is encrypted and transmitted on a secured network (SSL); we do not store your credit card numbers in our database or on our servers. Credit card numbers are processed and tokenized by a secure credit card processing company 

Although we do our best to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of personal information transmitted to our websites. Rocky Mountain ATV/MC has established policies and protocols for managing any potential data breach. Please do your part in protecting any other personal information against unauthorized use. Keep your password safe and confidential, and be sure to sign off when finished using a shared computer. Also scan your computer regularly for viruses, malware, and spyware. 

### How We Use It

Your information helps us keep track of your past orders, returns, and interests. It helps us administer contests and other promotions, and informs our marketing research to help us make better business decisions. We do not use your personal information for automated decision-making or profiling. 

#### Your Access and Control over Information

You have a right to access and control your personal information held by Rocky Mountain ATV/MC. You may:

  * Obtain information regarding the collection, processing, and sharing of your personal information
  * Access the personal information we have obtained about you, if any
  * Correct your personal information
  * Delete your personal information
  * Request an electronic copy of your personal information
  * Object to the use of your personal information for certain purposes

You can also access and update your Rocky Mountain ATV/MC account information by logging into your account. To delete your account, please contact us by emailing [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#0e7d6b6d7b7c677a774e7c616d657763617b607a6f67606f7a78206d6163). Rocky Mountain ATV/MC will not discriminate against individuals who exercise these rights. 

#### Do Not Track Policy

Some browsers have a “do not track” feature that lets you tell websites that you do not want to have your online activities tracked. We currently do not respond to browser “do not track” signals. 

#### Marketing Activities

We may use your personal information to contact you regarding Rocky Mountain ATV/MC products, services, promotions, newsletters, and other marketing activities. You may opt out of receiving these promotional emails at any time by emailing [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#ccbfada0a9bf8cbea3afa7b5a1a3b9a2b8ada5a2adb8bae2afa3a1e2). If you opt out, we may still send you non-promotional emails relating to your account, to recent purchases, or to our ongoing business relations. 

#### Links to Other Sites and Social Sharing Features

Our websites may contain links to other sites that are not operated by us. If you click on a link to a third-party site, you will be directed to their site. We have no control over these sites, we cannot protect your personal data, and we strongly advise you to review the privacy policy of every site you visit. Our websites also offer social sharing features (such as the Facebook Like button) which lets you share actions you take on our websites with your friends or the public depending on the settings of your social sharing account. For more information about these social sharing features, please visit the privacy policy of the respective entity. 

### Changes to This Privacy Policy

We may update our Privacy Policy from time to time. We will notify you of any changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on this page. If we make any material changes to how we treat our customers’ personal information, we will notify you by email to the primary email address specified in your account, and through a notice on our website’s home page. You are responsible for ensuring we have an up-to-date active email address to contact you. You are advised to review this Privacy Policy periodically for any changes. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page. 

### California Residents

California residents may request a printed notice of the information we have collected and provided to other parties during the preceding year. To do so, please contact [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#d0a3b5b3a5a2b9a4a990a2bfb3bba9bdbfa5bea4b1b9beb1a4a6feb3bfbd). 

### Contact Information

If you have any questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, you can contact us [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#50233533252239242910223f333b293d3f253e2431393e3124267e333f3d).
